

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211













Total Experience: 22 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

**Highest Degree:** 

Associate Director seeking roles in Application Development, Project Management, Program Management, Release Management, Technology Management, Service Delivery Management, Resource Utilization, Production Support, Business Analysis, Salesforce, Java, Cobol

Current Designation: NA

Current Company: NA

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Role: Program Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Associate Director, Program Manager, Application Development, Project Management, Program Management, Release Management, Technology Management, Service Delivery Management, Resource Utilization, Production Support, Business Analysis, Salesforce, Java, Cobol

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

## Summary

Aresult-oriented, energetic professional having over 2 decades experience of Application Development, Maintenance and Production Support experience including 12 years in Project Manager/ Program Manager roles leading teams in Healthcare, BFS, Insurance, Life Science and Technology domains Directed technology planning and direction, strategy development, leadership and implementation, business and operational transformation execution, business solution delivery, and business development Coordinated between departments, suggested a proactive approach over a reactive one that spanned all teams involved in the full product value chain Established an architect function to ensure ample focus on ongoing activities and quality improvements on an architectural level in the existing code base.

# **Work Experience**

- NA as NA
- Sep 2010 to Till Date
- Cognizant Technology Solutions as Associate Director IT Sep 2006 to Jun 2020

Apr'13 - Mar'16: Xerox ND MMIS as Program Manager

Oct'12-Mar'13: Marsh Endeavour Program as Program Manager

Nov11-Jul'12: Medco CRS VB to .NET Conversion as Senior Manager - Projects

Jul'10- Oct'11: WellPoint/ Medisys - Senior Enrollment System as Project Manager

Feb'10-Jul'10: Microsoft LSG SE Maintenance as Project Manager

Feb'09-Feb'10: Euroclear - Single Platform Program as Project Manager

Mar'08 - Feb'09: Merck - Merck Research Labs (MRL) M&O as Project Manager

Sep'07 - Mar'08: Merck EMEA - univadis as Project Manager

Sep'06 - Sep'07: JPMC - ITS UK as Project Manager

Project: Emblem Health Location: New York, USA Bengaluru, India Period: Feb'16-Present Role: Salesforce Integration Manager, Portals Performance Validation Lead, DevOps Lead Description: Implementing SALESFORCE platform for the benefit of the Sales and Marketing business functions within Emblem Health; rolling out various Salesforce features at different intervals as part of the release plan. Integrating the Salesforce platform with the existing legacy applications has been a corner stone of the successful releases. Eventually, some of the legacy entities will be de-commissioned as the functions get seamlessly migrated over to the Salesforce platform. The client user community has been very enthusiastic about the modern platform that has already brought in high level of efficiency to their business processes.

DevOps: Directing a team of resources for: o Ensuring deployment of code into various lower environments using tools such as Chef. o Configuring performance validation tools such as AppDynamics for time slicing business transactions, setting up Load runner. o Establishing F5 rules for load balancing of servers, setting up ZUUL servers for dynamic routing of microservices. o Providing support to defect triaging team by sharing System, application logs. o Assuring all underlying TIL/ CIL services are enabled and running at all times. o Monitoring Memory, CPU utilization across a range of servers and taking preventive action to keep utilization below a desired threshold limit

# **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Performance Validation of Healthcare Portals for Employer, Provider, Member: Leading the Performance Validation of the new portals = developed for EmblemHealth Acting as SPOC from the Healthcare vertical and liaising with QCoE

Performance Team, PACE team, the Portal Product Team, SI Team and the Database Team to triage issues and meet the SLAs defined for all the business transactions on the portals Key Result Areas: Interfacing with Business Analysts and helping them gain understanding of the existing Legacy

applications, Portals and Database model; framing the requirements for integrating those applications with Salesforce CRM platform Ensuring that the Legacy Team thoroughly analyzed the business requirements received from the Salesforce Business analysts, identify gaps if any so those could be addressed by the BAs. Executing disparate technology and platform teams such as Data Warehouse, Mddleware (ESB), File transfer (NFT), healthcare platform (Facets), Portals, Document management system (Softheon) together in formulating various integration between legacy applications and Salesforce platform to meet client's business goals. Performing review of current state and end state Architecture diagram with the Enterprise Architecture team to provide critical inputs based on the understanding and knowledge of the existing applications. Generating Prod release plan for delivering the Integration solution as per the program timeline. Appraising Program management of risks that may impact delivery timelines and providing a mitigation plan so impact can be minimized or contained

- Cognizant as Associate Director Sep 2006 to Jun 2020
- Kanbay as Project Lead Jun 2005 to Sep 2006
- Accenture as EFT Project Aug 2002 to Jun 2005

Growth Path:

Aug'02-May03: Team Lead in Citigroup - Travelers, FAIDS Project Aug'03-Jun'05: Team Lead in Sallie Mae - EFT Project

^ Back to Top

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Karnataka University in 1989 PG: in 0

^ Back to Top

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
.NET, Java, Salesforce		
Legacy integration with Sales Cloud		
Cobol		
Eztrieve, DB2, IDMS		
ADSO, IMS, JCL, VSAM		
REXX		

^ Back to Top

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Marathi				
Kannada				

^ Back to Top

## **Affirmative Action**

## **Work Authorization**

Category: General Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

